Register of the United States Army European Command, Historical Division Typescript Studies, 1945-1954
Hoover Institution Archives
- B Series Manuscripts. (Box 5-28)
  - B-346 II Parachute Corps (25 Jul.-25 Aug. 1944). By Oberst Ernst Blauensteiner; 14 pp, 3 illus; 1946. Normandy. (Box 15)
  - B-347 Sixth SS Panzer Army Artillery. By Generalleutnant (Waffen-SS) Walter Staudinger; 15 pp, 1 illus. Role in the Ardennes offensive. (Box 15)
  - B-348 First Army (24 Mar.-8 May 1945). By Generalmajor Wolf Hauser; 25 pp, 7 illus; 1946. By the army chief of staff. (Box 15)
  - B-350 Panzer Division "Clausewitz" (1-21 Apr. 1945). By Generalleutnant Martin Unrein; 20 pp; 1947. (Box 15)
  - B-351 Sociology of German Officer Corps. By General der Infanterie G. Blumentritt; 13 pp; 1947. (Box 15)
  - B-354 First Parachute Army (28- Mar.-9 Apr. 1945). By General der Infanterie G. Blumentritt; 21 pp, 5 illus; 1947. East of the Rhine; interesting historical review. (Box 15)
  - B-355 13th Administrative Division (13 Apr.-1 May 1945). By Generalmajor Manfred Mueller; 7 pp, 1 illus; 1946. Reconnaissance staff without troops. (Box 16)
  - B-356 159th Infantry Division (22 Mar.- 4 Apr. 1945). By Generalmajor Heinrich Buercky; 28 pp, 12 illus; 1947. Central Germany. (Box 16)
  - B-357 416th Infantry Division (16 Feb.-6 May 1945). By Major i.G. Kurt Hold; 44 pp, 19 illus; 1946. On both banks of the Rhine. (Box 16)
  - B-358 Leibstandarte Adolf Hitler in Aug 1944. By Generalmajor der Waffen- SS Theodor Wisch; 6 pp; 1946. Questionnaire on the fighting in Normandy (Avranches, Falaise), August 1944. (Box 16)
  - B-359 467th Infantry Division (Correction of MS # B-310). By Generalleutnant Walter Poppe; 1 p; 1946. (Box 16)
  - B-360 2d Panzer Division (28 Mar.-4 Apr. 1945). By Generalmajor Oskar Munzel; 9 pp, 3 illus; 1947. Panzer Training Division "Thueringen"; commitment of an improvised force. (Box 16)
  - B-361 Provisional Army Blumentritt (10 Apr.-1 Jun 1945). By General der Infanterie G. Blumentritt; 30 pp, 4 illus; 1947. The last battle. (Box 16)
  - B-362 176th Infantry Division (1-30 Sep. 1944). By Generalmajor Christian Landau; 7 pp, 1 illus; 1947. (Box 16)
  - B-363 First Army (15 Sep.-7 Nov. 1944). By Oberst i.G. Atberf`Emmerich; 18 pp; 1947. (Box 16)
  - B-364 11th Panzer Division (15 Sep.-29 Oct. 1944). By Generalleutnant Wend von Wietersheim; 29 pp, 4 illus; 1947. (Box 16)
  - B-365 Twenty-Fifth Army (3 Feb.-28 Mar. 1945). By General der Infanterie G. Blumentritt; 16 pp, 1 illus; 1947. Holland. (Box 16)
  - B-366 Army Group G-Supply (26 Oct. 1944-6 May 1945). By Generalintendant Otto Witek; 88 pp; 1947. Supplying troops in southern and eastern France and in southern Germany. (Box 16)
  - B-367 XLVII Panzer Corps (23 Oct.-5 Dec. 1944). By General der Panzertruppen H. von Luettwitz; 38 pp, 3 illus;1947. By the corps commander. (Box 16)
  - B-368 6th Parachute Division (19 Nov. 1944-10 May 1945). By Generalmajor Rudolf Langhaeuser; 13 pp, 5 illus; 1947. (Box 16)
  - B-369 189th Infantry Division (14-19 Nov. 1944). By Generalmajor Joachim Degener; 21 pp, 2 illus; 1947. (Box 16)
  - B-373 commander based on personal diary. Delaying action in northern France and the Rhineland. (Box 16)
  - B-374 History and Public Opinion. By General der Infanterie G. Blumentritt; 31 pp; 1947. (Box 16)
  - B-375 Wehrkreis VII (12 Apr.-10 May 1945). By Generalleutnant Heinrich Greiner; 32 pp, 3 illus; 1947. The last days of the war along and south of the Danube. (Box 16)
  - B-376 Comments on the History of U.S. Seventh Army. By General der Infanterie Baptist Kniess; 7 pp; 1947. Southern France. (Box 16)
  - B-378 Feld Kommandantur 563-Montpellier (20 Feb.-20 Aug. 1944). By General major Friedrich Dernen; 13 pp, 3 illus; 1947. An administrative and security headquarters. Events in the Department of Herault; relations with the French population during the invasion. (Box 16)
  - B-379 553d Volks Grenadier Division (10-22 Nov. 1944). By Generalmajor Hans Bruhn; 84 pp; 7 illus; 1947. Combat in the Vosges Mountains. (Box 16)
  - B-380 467th, Replacement and Training Division. By Generalleutnant Rudolf Sintzenich; 18 pp, 2 illus; 1946. (Box 16)
  - B-381 16th Luftwaffe Field Division (1 Nov. 1943-1 Jun. 1944). By Generalleutnant Karl Sievers; 17 pp; 1947. Organization, training, and preparations for coast defense. (Box 16)
  - B-382 LXVI Corps (26-30 Mar 1945). By Generalleutnant Hermann Floerke; 24 pp; 2 illus; 1946. (Box 16)
  - B-383 LXVI Corps (30 Mar.-4 Apr. 1945). By Generalleutnant Hermann Floerke; 41 pp, 5 illus. Hesse. (Box 16)
  - B-388 352d Infantry Division (6 Jun. 1944). By Oberstleutnant Fritz Ziegelmann; 36 pp. D Day in Normandy. Extracts from the operations officer's telephone log. (Box 16)
  - B-389 Enemy Military Experience. By Generaloberst Lothar Rendulic; 5 pp; 1947. The application of foreign military experience. (Box 16)
  - B-390 Rendulic's Service in the East. By Generaloberst Dr. Lothar Rendulic; 8 pp. (Box 16)
  - B-391 Battle Group Buddenbrodc (16 Mar,-4 May 1945). By Generalmajor Jobst Frhr. von Buddenbrock; 6 pp. (Box 16)
  - B-392 XIII Corps (22-31 Mar .1945). By Generalleutnant Ralph von Oriola; 17 pp; 1946. East of the Rhine. (Box 16)
  - B-393 Fifth Panzer,Army Artillery (Ardennes). By Generalleutnant Richard Metz; 80 pp, 2 illus; 1946. (Box 16)
  - B-394. Twelfth Army (11 Apr.- May 1945). By General der Panzertruppen Walt. Wendt; 7 pp; 1946. On both banks of the Elbe. (Box 17)
  - B-395 Photograph of Field Marshal Model. By Generalleutnant Fritz Bayerlein; 3 pp, 1 illus. History of a photograph taken on 20 March 1945. (Box 17)
  - B-399 Psychological Warfare. By General der Infanterie Enno v. Rintelen; 8 pp. Comments on Italian and German propaganda in Italy, by the former German military attaché to Rome. (Box 17)
  - B-400 20 July 1944. By General der Infanterie Alexander von Falkenhausen; 3 pp; 1947. Comments on the 20 July 1944 attempt to assassinate Hitler. (Box 17)
  - B-401 II Parachute Corps (Dec. 1942-24 Jul. 1944). By General der Fallschirmtruppen Eugen Meindl; 41 pp; 1946. By the corps commander. (Box 17)
  - B-402 Feld Kommandantur 800--Draguignan (12-17 Aug. 1944). By Generalmajor Ludwig Bieringer; 33 pp, 1 illus; 1947. An administrative and security headquarters. (Box 17)
  - B-403 711th Infantry Division (1 Apr. 1943-24 Jul. 1944). By Generalleutnant Joseph Reichert; 24 pp; 1947. By the division commander. (Box 17)
  - B-404 Wehrkreis XII (22 Mar.-11 May 1945). By Generalleutnant Ernst Faeckenstedt; 22 pp, 9 illus; 1947. Central Germany. (Box 17)
  - B-405 Wehrkreis XII (22-31 Mar. 1945). By General der Artillerie Herbert Osterkamp; 4 pp; 1947. Comments on MS # B-404. (Box 17)
  - B-406 Battle Group "Runge" (21-25 Mar 1945). By Generalmajor Hans Boelsen; 9 pp, 3 illus; 1947. On the Rhine. (Box 17)
  - B-407 172d Administrative Division (25-28 Mar. 1945). By Generalmajor Hans Boelsen; 9 pp, 3 illus; 1947. Fighting in the Taunus. (Box 17)
  - B-408 Antitank Division West--Seventh Army. By Oberstfeutnant i.G. Ulrich Klimke; 8 pp; 1947. The organization and mission of this improvised unit, which was never committed in actual combat. Includes views on future organization. (Box 17)
  - B-409 LIII Corps (23-29 Mar. 1945). By Generalleutnant Fritz Bayerlein; 12 pp, 16 illus; 1946. (Box 17)
  - B-410 XII SS Corps (26 Jan.-4 Mar. 1945). By Oberst Ulrich Ulms. 47 pp, 4 illus; 1947. Between the Roer and Rhine Rivers. (Box 17)
  - B-411 353d Infantry Division (19 Sep.-1 Oct. 1944). By Generalleutnant Paul Mahlmann; 4 pp, 5 illus; 1947. Fighting in the forest west of Huertgen. (Box 17)
  - B-412 XIII SS Corps (1 Sep.-15 Nov. 1944). By Oberst Kurt v. Einem; 18 pp, 8 illus; 1946. (Box 17)
  - B-413 OB West, Special Report. By General der Kavallerie Rudolf Koch- Erpach; 18 pp, 1 illus; 1947. German morale and fighting strength in the spring of 1945. (Box 17)
  - B-414 Army Group H (10 Mar.-9 May 1945). By Oberst i.G. Rolf Geyer; 47 pp, 17 illus; 1946. Activities of Commander in Chief Northwest. (Box 17)
  - B-415 12th Infantry Division (22 Sep.-22 Oct. 1944). By Generalleutnant Gerhard Engel; 43 pp, 1 illus; 1946. (Box 17)
  - B-416 11th Panzer Division (28 Oct.-17 Dec. 1944). By Generalleutnant Wend von Wietersheim; 21 pp, 4 iLlus; 1946. Lorraine. (Box 17)
  - B-417 11TH Panzer Division (20 Dec. 1944-10 Feb. 1945). By Generalleutnant W. von Wietersheim; 11 pp, 2 illus; 1947. The Rhineland. (Box 17)
  - B-419 18th Luftwaffe Field Division ( 6 Jun.-24 Jul. 1944). By Generalleutnant Joachim Tresckow; 16 pp, 5 illus; 1947. Normandy. (Box 17)
  - B-420 The German Defense of Marseille, Aug. 1944. By Generalleutnant Hans Schaefer; 22 pp; 1947. Comments on French reports. (Box 17)
  - B-421 German (OB Southwest) Estimate of Situation Prior to Allied Invasion of Southern France. By Generaloberst Johannes Blaskowitz; 3 pp; 1947. Comments on the report by General Roettiger concerning the landing in southern France (MS # B-330). (Box 17)
  - B-422 Liaison Staff 659--Pyrenees. By Generalmajor Leo Mayr; 9 pp; 1947. Organization and administrative activities in occupied France. (Box 17)
  - B-423 Withdrawal of Rear Guard 159th Division from Bordeaux to Poitiers. By Generalmajor Gustav Seiz; 3 pp; 1947. (Box 17)
  - B-424 85th Infantry Division (31 Jul.-8 Aug. 1944). By Oberstleutnant Kurt Arthur Schuster; 7 pp, 2 illus; 1947. A division on the march to Normandy. (Box 17)
  - B-425 89th Infantry Division (8-15 Aug. 1944), By Oberst Hasso Neitzel; 10 pp, 2 illus; 1947. (Box 17)
  - B-426 LVIII Panzer Corps Artillery (1 Aug.-6 Sep. 1944). By Generalmajor Gerhard Triepel; 5 pp. A corps artillery commander in Normandy. (Box 17)
  - B-427 Brest--43d Infantry Division (May -18 Sep. 1944). By Oberst i.G. Rudolf Kogard; 35 pp, 3 illus; 1947. Western Brittany before and during the invasion. (Box 17)
  - B-430 LXIV Corps (28 Jan.-7 Feb.1945). By General der Artillerie Max Grimmeis; 31 pp, 3 illus; 1947. In the upper Rhine bridgehead. (Box 17)
  - B-431 German Last Days in Pilsen. By Generalmajor Gerhard Mueller; 9 pp; 1947. The capture of Pilsen by the U.S. 16th Armored Division. Attitude of the Czecho-Slovakian population in the last months of the war. (Box 17)
  - B-432 352d Infantry Division (5 Dec. 1943-6 Jun. 1944). By Oberstleutnant Fritz Ziegelmann; 42 pp, 6 ilius; 1946. Organization and fighting on D day in Normandy. (Box 17)
  - B-433-B-439 352d Infantry Division (7 Jun.-10 Jul. 1944). By Oberstleutnant Fritz to Ziegelmann; 2 Vol., 72 pp, 7 illus, 1946-1947. Continuation of MS # B-432. (Box 17)
  - B-440 Army Group G (May-Jul. 1944). By Generalleutnant Heinz von Gyldenfeldt; 37 pp, 2 illus. Southern France. By the army group chief of staff. See also MSS # B-488, B-552, B-588, B-589, in which the same author reports on this unit's activities until late September 1944. (Box 17)
  - B-441 21st Panzer Division (1942-Jul.1944). By Generalleutnant Edgar Feuchtinger; 50 pp; 1947. Organization and fighting to 3 July 1944 in Normandy. (Box 17)
  - B-442 LXXXV Corps (21 Jan.-23 Mar. 1945). By General der Infanterie- Bad Kniess; 2 pp, 1 illus; 1947. In the Saar. (Box 17)
  - B-443 First Army (8 Nov.-20 Dec. 1944).By Oberst i.G. Albert Emmerich; 28 pp; 1947. (Box 17)
  - B-444 276thVolks Grenadier, Division (21 Jan-17 Mar 1945). By Oberst Werner Wagner; 33 pp, 8 illus. (Box 17)
  - B-445 LVIII Panzer Corps (24 Jul -15 Sep-1944). By General der Panzertruppen Walter Krueger; 34 pp, 5 illus. In France. (Box 17)
  - B-446 Liaison Staff 732 (20 Aug-5 Sep 1944). By Generglmajor Johannes Hahn; 12 pp, 2 illus; 1947. Pau, France. (Box 18)
  - B-447 Seventh Army (1 Sep. 1944-25 Jan. 1945). By General der Panzertruppen Erich Brandenberger; 50 pp, 1 illus; 1946. Questionnaire on activities in France and Germany, from 1 Sep. 1944 to the Ardennes offensive. (Box 18)
  - B-448 The French Resistance Movement. By Oberst Albert Emmerich; 3 pp; 1946. (Box 18)
  - B-449 Nineteenth Army--Fortress Engineer (1943-Aug. 1944). By Generalmaior Wilhelm Uilersperger; 39 pp, 2 illus; 1947. Mediterranean coast; technical. (Box 18)
  - B-450 Army Group G (20 Feb.- 22 Mar. 1945). By Oberst Horst Wilutzky; 58 pp, 12 illus. (Box 18)
  - B-451 708th Volks Grenadier Division (15 Sep.-17 Nov. 1944). By Generalmajor Josef Paul Krieger; 16 pp, 2 illus; 1947. In the Vosges, November 1944. (Box 18)
  - B-452 16th Infantry Division (15 Sep.-10 Dec. 1944). By Generalleutnant Ernst Haeckel; 25 pp, 4 illus. (Box 18)
  - B-453 6th Parachute Division (11 Mar.-1 Apr. 1945). By Generalmajor Rudolf Langhaeuser; 11 pp, 1 illus.; 1947. (Box 18)
  - B-454 Balance of Power. By. General de Infanterie Georg von Sodenstern; 15 Pp, 8 illus; 1947. Comments on the present situation in Europe (1947) and the outlook for the future. (Box 18)
  - B-455 352d Infantry Division (l1-18 Jul. 1944). By Oberstleutnant Fritz Ziegelmann; 10 pp, 1 illus; 1947. (Box 18)
  - B-456 2d Panzer Division (21-26 Dec. 1944). By Oberstleutnant Ruediger Weiz; 10 pp. In the Ardennes. (Box 18)
  - B-457 National Redoubt. By Gauleiter Franz Hofer; 25 pp. A report by the Gauleiter of the Tyrol on German and U. S. views of the "Alpine Redoubt" in 1944. (Box 18)
  - B-458 National Redoubt. By Gauleiter Franz Hofer; 36 pp. Apparently summaries of much longer reports by the former Gauleiter of Tyrol. They cover the last months of the war and the efforts to consolidate the German. effort in the Alps in conjunction with the German military command. (Box 18)
  - B-459 National Redoubt. By General der Gebirgstruppen Georg von Hengl; 12 pp; 1946. Personal report by General von Hengl. Purely historical. (Box 18)
  - B-460 Evaluation of Manuscripts Concerning National Redoubt. By General der Gebirgstruppen Georg von Hengl; 5 pp; 1946. Comments on ten earlier reports. (Box 18)
  - B-461 The Alpine Redoubt. By General der Gebirgstruppen Georg von Hengl; 17 pp; 1947. A. final historical survey of this "spectre"; of historical value. (Box 18)
  - B-462 340th Grenadier Division (2 Sep.-25 Dec. 1944). By Oberstleutnant i.G. Hans-Hubert Voigt; 28 pp, 8 illus;1947. Good report on combat in the Rhineland. Available in USAREUR in German only. (Box 18)
  - B-463 Nineteenth Army (4 Jan.-21 Mar. 1945). By Oberst Kurt Brandstaedter; 39 pp, 26 illus; 1947. Fighting with exhausted troops against superior forces. (Box 18)
  - B-464 352d Infantry Division (19-24 Jul. 1944). By Oberstleutnant Fritz Ziegelmann; 5 pp, 1 illus. Combat south of St. Lo. (Box 18)
  - B-465 3d Panzer Grenadier Division (16-28 Dec. 1944). By Generalmajor Walter Denkert; 29 pp, 4 illus; 1947. (Box 18)
  - B-468 LXIV Corps (1 Nov.-31 Dec. 1944). By General der Infanterie Helmut Thumm; 19 pp, 7 illus; 1947. Includes remarks on delaying action. (Box 19)
  - B-469 91st Airborne Division Artillery (18 Jun.-31 Jul. 1944). By Generalmajor Gerhard Triepel; 9 pp; 1947. (Box 19)
  - B-470 9th SS Panzer Division (20 Jun.-24 Jul. 1944). By Generalmajor Sylvester Stadler; 22 pp; 1947. A clear picture of frontline conditions. (Box 19)
  - B-471 Fortress Lorient--Normandy--Special Questions. By Generalmajor Julius Kuse; 6 pp; 1947. (Box 19)
  - B-472 Fifth Panzer Army (14 Sep.-15 Oct. 1944). By Oberst Wolf Von Kahlden; 28 pp, 6 illus; 1947. (Box 19)
  - B-473 LVIII Panzer Corps Artillery (18 Sep.-1 Nov. 1944). By Generalmajor Gerhard Triepel; 6 pp. (Box 19)
  - B-474 Activities of the Artillery Headquarters in the Strassbourg-Saarbourg Area in Fall 1944. By Generalmajor Walter Beisswaenger; 7 pp; 1947. Organization of positions and static batteries. (Box 19)
  - B-475 Fifteenth Army (15 Sep.-10 Nov. 1944). By General der Infanterie Gustav von Zangen; 54 pp, 1 illus; 1947. (Box 19)
  - B-476 6th SS Mountain Division (Sept. 1944-26 Jan. 1945). By SS Gruppenfuehrer Karl Brenner; 13 pp, 8 illus; 1947. A day-by-day historical record. (Box 19)
  - B-477 LXVI Corps (23 Dec. 1944-2 Jan. 1945). By General der Artillerie Walter Lucht; 9 pp, 3 illus. (Box 19)
  - B-480 St. Nazaire Naval Forces. (Normandy). By Konteradmiral Hans Mirow; 8 pp; 1947. Answers by Naval Commander Loire to a questionnaire on the invasion. (Box 19)
  - B-481 First Army Artillery (23 Mar.-8 May 1945). By Generalleutnant Julius Braun; 34 pp, 3 illus; 1947. (Box 19)
  - B-482 LXIV Corps (1-16 Nov. 1944). By Major i.G. Kurt Schuster; 24 pp, 4 illus; 1947. (Box 19)
  - B-483 Languedoc Naval Defense (1944). By Vizeadmiral Erich Schulte- Moenting; 18 pp; 1947. Coast defense in the sector of Naval Commander Languedoc. Technical. (Box 19)
  - B-484 Military Attaché to Washington (1933-1941). By General der Artillerie Friedrich von Boetticher; 58 pp; 1947. Comments on military and political affairs. (Box 19)
  - B-486 LVIII Panzer Corps (6 Jun.-24 Jul. 1944). By General der Panzertruppen Walter Krueger; 18 pp, 2 illus; 1946. Corps activities prior to the invasion; a historical report on organization and training. (Box 19)
  - B-487 XIII SS Corps (16 Nov.-5 Dec. 1944). By Generalleutnant der Waffen-SS Max Simon; 17 pp; 1947. (Box 19)
  - B-489 352d Infantry Division (25-30 Jul. 1944). By Oberstleutnant Fritz Ziegelmann; 11 pp, 1 illus; 1947. (Box 19)
  - B-490 352d Infantry Division (Conclusions, 6 Jun.-30 Jul. 1944). By Oberstleutnant Fritz Ziegelmann; 17 pp, 4 illus; 1947. Very interesting and valuable evaluation from the viewpoint of a fighting infantry division. (Box 19)
  - B-491 First Army (1-11 Nov. 1944). By General der Infanterie Kurt von to Tippelskirch; 2 vols, 18 pp, 1 illus; 1947. Vol. I, Estimate of the Situation (Box 19)
  - B-492 Vol. II, Report on Combat (Lorraine). (Box 19)
  - B-493 LXIV Corps (end of Sep. 1944). By Major i.G. Kurt Schuster; 11 pp, 2 illus; 1947. A special study to show the weaknesses of German defense at the time. (Box 19)
  - B-494 XIII Corps (29 Jan.-20 Feb. 1945). By General der Infanterie Hans Felber, 47 pp, 1 illus; 1947. Interesting historical study. (Box 19)
  - B-495 Italian-German Cooperation (Oct. 1936-Nov. 1940). By General der Infanterie Enno von Rintelen; 49 pp, 1947. Most interesting report by the German Military Attaché in Rome at that time. Covers a wide range of political and military events in the Mediterranean area. (Box 19)
  - B-496 331st Infantry Division (1 Apr.-25 Jun. 1944). By Generalmajor Heinz Furbach; 15 pp, 2 illus. Defense preparations in France. (Box 19)
  - B-497 Mulhouse--Wehrmacht Commandant (Jul. 1944-Jan. 1945). By Generalmajor Hermann Harttmann; 7 pp; 1947. Supplement to MS # B-083. (Box 19)
  - B-498 Defense of Mulhouse Area Against Airborne Attack. By Generalmajor Hermann Harttman; 7 pp, 1 illus; 1947. Preparations for defense against airborne landings in the Mulhouse area, 1944. (Box 19)
  - B-499 Events Leading up to 20 July 1944. By General der Infanterie Georg von Sodenstern; 47 pp; 1947. (Box 19)
  - B-500 Nineteenth Army (22 Mar.-5 May 1945). By Oberst Kurt Brandstaedter; 54 pp, 6 illus; 1947. Fighting on the upper Rhine and in southern Germany. (Box 19)
  - B-501 LIII Corps Situation (27 Feb. 1945). By Oberst i.G. Werner Bodenstein; 14 pp, 1 illus; 1947. A detailed situation estimate. (Box 19)
  - B-502 353d Infantry Division (3 Oct.-25 Nov. 1944). By Generalleutnant Paul to Mahlmann; 2 vols, 11 pp, 2 illus; 1947. Reorganization of the division. (Box 19)
  - B-503 (Box 19)
  - B-504 LXIV Corps Defensive Construction (16 Sep. 1944-25 Feb. 1945). By Generalmajor Hans Taeglichsbeck; 16 pp, 3 illus; 1947. Reconnaissance and organization of rear positions by LXIV Corps (Vosges and upper Rhine. (Box 19)
  - B-505 49th Infantry Division (1943-Jul. 1944). By Generalleutnant Siegfried Macholz; 30 pp, 5 illus. Defense problems on the Channel Coast, 1944; views on fortification. (Box 20)
  - B-506 LVIIII Panzer Corps Artillery (1 Nov. 1944-1 Feb. 1945). By Generalmajor Gerhard Triepel; 10 pp; 1947. (Box 20)
  - B-507 XC Corps (20 Mar.-10 May 1945). By General der Infanterie Erich Petersen; 20 pp, 4 illus; 1947. Rhine and central Germany. (Box 20)
  - B-508 2d Parachute Division (8 Mar.-16 Apr. 1945). By Generalleutnant Walter Lackner; 5 pp, 2 illus. (Box 20)
  - B-509 II Air Force Corps (6-28 Jun. 1944). By General der Flieger Alfred Buelowius; 5 pp. Questionnaire on the Normandy invasion. (Box 20)
  - B-510 59th Infantry Division (4 Sep., 5 Sep., 24 Sep. 1944). By Generalleutnant Walter Poppe; 1p; 1947. Combat in Belgium. (Box 20)
  - B-513 German General Staff Officers, Casualties. By Generalleutnant Bernhard von Claer; 5 pp, 6 illus. An incomplete study on the fate of some leading German generals. (Box 20)
  - B-514 Nineteenth Army (15 Aug.-15 Sep. 1944). By Oberst Fritz Schulz; 42 pp; 1946. Engagements in southern France. (Box 20)
  - B-517 159th Reserve Infantry Division (5-14 Sep. 1944). By Generalleutnant Otto Kohl; 4 pp. (Box 20)
  - B-518 Comments on History of U.S. Seventh Army. By Generalleutnant Walter Botsch; 39 pp; 1946. (Box 20)
  - B-519 Defenses in the Vosges (8 Aug.-15 Oct. 1944). By General der Infanterie Hans Joachim Schmidt; 4 pp; 1947. Supplement to MS # B-043. (Box 20)
  - B-520 257th Volks Grenadier Division (25 Oct. 1944-15 Jan. 1945). By Oberstleutnant i.G. Ernst Linke; 27 pp, 3 illus; 1947. Commitment of a newly organized infantry division in wooded terrain. (Box 20)
  - B-521 9th Volks Grenadier Division (1 Nov. 1944-5 Feb. 1945). By Generalmajor Werner Kolb; 33 pp, 5 illus; 1947. (Box 20)
  - B-522 12th SS Panzer Division (15 Nov.-15 Dec. 1944). By Generalmajor Hugo Kraas; 14 pp, 1 illus; 1947. (Box 20)
  - B-523 LVIII Panzer Corps (23 Mar.-16 Apr. 1945). By Generalleutnant Walter Botsch; 15 pp; 1947.. (Box 20)
  - B-524 The Invasion of Greece. By General der Infanterie Hans von Greiffenberg; 42 pp, 5 illus; 1947. Overall review. (Box 20)
  - B-526 276th Infantry Division (1 Jan.-20 Aug. 1944). By Generalleutnant Kurt Badinski; 73 pp, 4 illus; 1947. Normandy and northern France. (Box 20)
  - B-527 19th Volks Grenadier Division (1 Sep. 1944-27 Apr. 1945). By Generalmajor Karl Britzelmayr; 61 pp, 4 illus; 1946. (Box 20)
  - B-528 271st Infantry Division (Mar-13 Aug. 1944). By Generalleutnant Paul Danhauser; 7 pp, 4 illus; 1947. Supplement to MS # B-256. (Box 20)
  - B-530 159th Infantry Division (1939-15 Sep. 1944). By Generalmajor Friedrich Dernen; 12 pp; 1947. (Box 20)
  - B-531 338th Infantry Division (11 Feb.-3 Mar. 1945). By Generalmajor Wolf Ewert; 13 pp, 3 illus; 1947. (Box 20)
  - B-532 346th Infantry Division (24 Jul.-15 Sep. 1944). By Oberst i.G. Paul Frank; 52 pp, 12 illus; 1946. Normandy and Belgium. (Box 20)
  - B-533 176th Infantry Division (1 Oct. 1944-15 Jan. 1945). By Generalmajor Christian Landau; 15 pp, 5 illus; 1947. (Box 20)
  - B-534 Liaison Staff 659 (1 Jun.-19 Aug. 1944). By Generalmajor Leo Mayr; 9 pp; 1947. (Box 20)
  - B-535 559th Volks Grenadier Division (20 Feb.-21 Mar. 1945). By Generalmajor Kurt von Muehlen; 8 pp, 4 illus; 1947. (Box 20)
  - B-536 89th Infantry Division (15 Aug.-16 Sep. 1944). By Oberst Hasso Neitzel; 13 pp, 2 illus; 1947. (Box 20)
  - B-539 Combat Actions (15-22 Sep. 1944). By Generalleutnant Otto Ottenbacher; 4 pp; 1947. (See MS # B-538). (Box 20)
  - B-540 272d Infantry Division (15 Dec. 1943-26 Jul. 1944). By General der lnfanterie Friedrich Schack; 19 pp, 3 illus; 1947 Activation; training; combat in Normandy. (Box 20)
  - B-541 3d Parachute Division (Jan.-Aug. 1944). By Generalleutnant Richard Schimpf; 28 pp, 3 illus; 1947. (Box 20)
  - B-542 70th Infantry Division (10-22 Sep. 1944) and 331st Infantry Division (15 Jul.-5 Sep. 1944). By Generalleutnant Walter Steinmueller; 21 pp; 1947. (Box 20)
  - B-544 18th Luftwaffe Field Division (13-18 Sep. 1944). By Generalleutnant Joachim von Tresckow; 16 pp, 3 illus; 1947. Belgium. (Box 20)
  - B-545 Strasbourg (Nov. 1944). By Generalmajor Franz Vaterrodt; 22pp; 1 illus; 1947. (Box 20)
  - B-546 47th Infantry Division (8 Aug.-4 Sep. 1944). By Generalmajor Carl Wahle; 12 pp. Supplement to MS # B-176. Delaying action in northern France and Belgium. (Box 21)